Vishal Virodhia

iOS Developer

E-2137A, Palam Vihar Gurgaon, Haryana 122017

+91 7696009955 virodhia.vishal@gmail.com in/vishalvirodhia git/vishalvirodhia

Profile

Senior iOS Developer with 10+ years of experience building and scaling mobile apps using Swift, Combine, SwiftUI and Objective-C. Led teams delivering AI, chat, and e-commerce apps with over 100K users. Skilled in optimizing app performance, Firebase integration, and full App Store lifecycle.

Technical Skills

Languages: Swift, Objective-C, SwiftUI
Frameworks: UIKit, Combine, ReactiveSwift
Tools: Xcode, Firebase, Git, Jira, APNS, Fastlane,
Other: MVC, MVVM, Agile/Scrum, Appstore Deployment

Experience

Hive.Ai / Sr. iOS Developer

Feb, 2019 - PRESENT, Gurgaon

- Leading a team of 5 iOS developers in delivering an Al-based art generator app, building new features for existing apps, and maintaining legacy codebases.
- Spearheaded architecture and feature delivery for Al Art Generator
- Collaborated with design team to define intuitive UX and app features
- Improved CI/CD pipeline using Fastlane and Github Actions
- Experience in documenting in various phases of the project including technical, business and functional presentation.

Click Labs / Sr. iOS Developer

March, 2016 - Jan, 2019, Chandigarh

- Worked to meet client deadlines.
- Effectively multi-tasked and worked well with internal and external teams.

- Effectively translated client requirements into application designs and system requirements.
- Determining operational feasibility by defining the problem, analyzing requirements, and assessing proposed solutions.

Solitaire Infosys Inc / iOS Developer

Nov, 2014 - March, 2016, Mohali

- Learning industry standard coding structure and applying gained knowledge to live projects

ECIL Rapiscan / Consultant Engineer

March, 2012 - March, 2014, New Delhi

- Consultant Engineer – Installed and configured surveillance infrastructure across multiple sites.

Education

Kurukshetra University, Kurukshetra / B.Tech

Aug, 2007 - July, 2011,

Projects Links

- Hive Work

https://apps.apple.com/in/app/hive-work/id1398800742

- Chatous

https://apps.apple.com/in/app/chatous-chat-with-new-people/id698 054232

- Secret Spa

https://apps.apple.com/in/app/secret-spa/id1000723800

- Home Solutions

https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/home-solutions-from-john-lewis/id 1238178445?mt=8

- Butler Tip

https://itunes.apple.com/kw/app/butlertip/id1056492719?mt=8